Center for Community Studies; Records ua652.004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Activities and Programs, 1825-1976; 2; 12 cubic ft.
  - Saint Mary's School, Undated (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 44)
  - Student,, Education 317, Student Report, 1951 (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 45)
  - Student, Student Project, 1957 (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 46)
  - San Jose Program, Developing the Content of the, Chapter 5, Undated (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 47)
  - Schedule for Analysis of Community Action Programs, Undated (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 48)
  - Schedules, 1958-1976 (Box 8 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 49)
  - Scheible, Mary, 1951 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - The School Administrator and Public Problems in the 60s, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - School of Education Curriculum Committee, 1972 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - School Public Relations, 1948-1951 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - School Taxations, 1950 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Schools and Institutions, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Second Annual First Year Teachers Clink, 1952 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Second Cortland Conference, 1952-06 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Second Eastern College Conference on Functional Education, 1953 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Secondary School Curriculum in New York State, 1959-1960 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Service Organizations Report, Albany, 1951-1956 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Services to Art and Culture, Photographs, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Services to Farmers, Photographs, 1953-1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Services to Forestry, Photographs, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Services to the Home, Photographs, 1953 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Services to Industry, Photographs, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Services to Schools, Photographs, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Services to Television and Radio, Photographs, 1953-1954 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Setauket Project, 1953 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Sherman, Arnold, 1973 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Student, Dissertation Proposal, 1965 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Student, Education 201, 1951 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Smith, C. Curien, New Wine in Old Bottles, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Student, Student Project, 1957 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Social Problems and Change, 1967 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Social Services in Schools, 1957-1964 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Some Observations and Suggestions by Alfred J. Cali, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Sovereignty, Situations, and Security, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Special Education, 1967 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Special Projects, 1964-1965 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Speech Therapy Clinic, Photographs, 1955 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Standing, T.G., 1965-1966 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Standing, T.G. ,The Problems of Consensus in the Modern Community, 1962 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - State Carities Aid Associations, 1964 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - State University College for Teachers at Buffalo, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 27)
  - State University, Rensselaerville Institute Programs, 1961 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 28)
  - A Statistical Study of the Wallingford School System, 1946 September (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 29)
  - Structural and Functional Change for Cooperation as an Aspect of Complex Organization Adaptation, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 30)
  - Student and Academic Conference, 1976 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 31)
  - Student Community Job Assignments, 1952 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 32)
  - Student Details, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 33)
  - Student Details, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 34)
  - Student Interviews, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 35)
  - Student Opinion Panel, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 36)
  - Student Opinion Panel, Undated (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 37)
  - Student Participation in College and Community Activities, 1950 (Box 9 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 38)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1947 (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1947 (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951 (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951 (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951 (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 10 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - "A Study of the Community Aspirations of Amsterdam, New York", 1964 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Supplementary Information on Assistantships and Fellowships, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Surveys, Students, 1954-1961 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Swimming Surveys, 1962 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Swire, Leslie, Educational Philosophy, 1976 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Syracuse University Students Development Test, 1946 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Teacher In-service Education Inventory, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Teaching Internship, 1964 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Temporary Shelter and Detention Care of Children in Albany and Rensselaer Counties, 1953-1954 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Term Papers, Students, 1952-1953 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Testing Materials, 1951 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Third Annual Curriculum Conference for School Administrators: The Disaffected Child, 1964 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Student, 1952 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Trends in High School Subjects, 1948-1949 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - Twenty-Second Annual Meeting of the Society for Applied Anthropology, 1963 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 27)
  - Student, 1976 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 28)
  - The University Certificate, Undated (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 29)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1949-1953 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 30)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1950-1955 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 31)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1950-1955 (Box 11 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 32)
  - The University of the State of New York, Education Department, 1962 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1951-1973 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1954-1975 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1960-1962 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1962-1965 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1965-1970 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Van Corlaer School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Vaughn, Harold A. Jr., 1951 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Vassar Summer Institute "What Can Communities Do?", 1952 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Student, Educational Philosophy 601, 1976 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - What is the Nature of the Problem Facing our Communities, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Wick, Rollo E., Correspondence, 1951 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Student, Dissertation Proposal, 1964 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Woodlawn School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Woodlawn School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Workshop Plans, 1951 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Workshops, 1952 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Workshops, 1952 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Wynne, John P., Philosophies of Educations, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Yates School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Yates School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Student, 1951 (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Zoller School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Zoller School, Undated (Box 12 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Courses, 1951-1953 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Census Classification Project, 1825-1890 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Students, The Community Centered School, 1952 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Geneseo-Cortland Conference, 1951-1952 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - High School Student Logs, 1937-1939 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Illich, Ivan, Why We Must Abolish Schooling, Undated (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - New York College for Teachers Student Participation Study, 1954 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Projective Devices, 1952 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Public Opinion Polls, 1953 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Research, 1951 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1935-1938 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1937 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1937 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1938 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1938 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1940 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1952 March 20 (Box 14 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - Survey of High School Student Activities, 1952 (Box 15 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Surveys on Social Agencies, Undated (Box 15 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
- Publications, 1946-1968; 3; 1.2 cubic ft.
  This series includes newsletters, reports, and studies published both by the Center for Community Studies and other organizations. Newsletters include the Center for Community Studies' Education Newsletter and the State University College of Albany's Faculty Bulletin of Information (F.B.I.). This series also includes articles, surveys and publications on prisons (such as Sing Sing), and segregation.
  - The ABCs of Local School Districts in New York State, 1960 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 1)
  - The Academically Talented: Problems and Programs, 1961 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel J., Sense & Nonsense About Race, New York, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel and W.M. Krogman, Race Against Time: An Introductory Anthropology for Young, Undated (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 4)
  - American Unity: To Secure These Rights, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Americas Tenth Man, Southern Regional Council, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Amsterdam Survey, Undated (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bienstok, Theodore, and William C. Sayres, Problems of Secondary Education in International Perspectives, 1959-02 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Center for Community Studies, Newsletter, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Charting Intercultural Education, 1954-1955 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Cole, Stewart G., and Helen G. Troger, How Can Majority and Minority Groups Contribute to Democracy? Democratic Discussions No. 10, 1943-1944 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 11)
  - College-Community Relationships in New York State, 1953 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Community, 1958 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Coolidge,Calvin, Address by the President (1925), Jewish Contributions to American Democracy, 1940 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Education Newsletter, 1951-1953 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Faculty Bulletin of Information, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, A Study of the Socio-Economic Status of a Group of Public School Children with Hearing Defects, Child Development 22.3, 1951 September (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, Teachers Problems with Hard of Hearing Children, Journal of Educational Research, 1949 April (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Fellowship House, Extinguish Hatred, Philadelphia, Undated (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Formation of Educational Policies: A Comparative Analysis, 1968 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Grier, Eunice, and George, Race Relations in the Albany-Troy Area: A Profile for 1957, 1957 November (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Halsey, Margaret, Some of My Best Friends are Soldiers, New York, 1944 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Hightower, Estelle, Race Relations in the South, New York, 1942 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Horner, Harlan H., Education in New York State, 1784-1954 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Improving InterGroup Relations in School and Community Life, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Intercultural Education through the Social Studies, 1945 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Eric A., Intolerance, New York City, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 27)
  - The July 1953 Prophylaxis Program for Poliomyelitis in Chemung Audsteuben Counties, 1954 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 28)
  - McEntire, Davis, and Robert B. Powers, A Guide to Race Relations For Police Officers, Police Training Bulletin, Department of Justice, State of California, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 29)
  - Members of the Staff of Junior High School 47, A New Approach To The Education of Two and Three Year Old Deaf Children, Volta Review, 1949 May-June (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 30)
  - Nelson, Robert L., The Negro in Athletics, New York, 1940 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 31)
  - Nelson, Rose K., and Dorothy L. Cole, The Negros Contribution to Music in America, New York, 1941 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 32)
  - Newsletter from the State University of New York, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 33)
  - Preparing the Offender in the Institutions of the New York State Department of Corrections, 1954 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 34)
  - The Problem of Violence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 35)
  - Sing Sing Prison, 1953 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 36)
  - State Education Department, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 37)
  - A Survey of the Humanagement of a Public School System, 1949 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 38)
  - Survey Graphic: Segregation, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 39)
  - Vickery, William E., and Morris Edward Opler, A Redefinition of Prejudice for Purposes of Social Science Research, Human Relations 1.4, 1948 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 40)